http://www.hpu.edu/about-us/privacy-policy.html

Privacy Policy
PLEASE READ THE FOLLOWING CAREFULLY.
THIS PAGE PROVIDES GENERAL INFORMATION ABOUT THE PRIVACY POLICY OF THIS WEBSITE.  This Privacy Policy covers the HPU.edu website and all other ‘mini-sites’ within the HPU.edu website (collectively the “Website”), unless otherwise indicated on a specific website.
The contents of this Website are owned and operated by Hawai‘i Pacific University (HPU), whose business address is 1 Aloha Tower Drive, HI 96813. You may contact us by email at help@hpu.edu.  HPU is very concerned about the protection of online privacy for all our Website visitors and especially children. HPU’s policy is to respect and protect the privacy of our users. This statement tells you if and how we collect personally-identifying information from you and how we use it. Using the Internet should be a fun and safe experience and we want to help you make it so.
WHAT INFORMATION IS COLLECTED
HPU.edu websites that incorporate this Privacy Policy may use online data entry forms to collect personally identifiable information, including your name and contact information (email, address, telephone number) and other identifiers in order to allow you to provide website feedback, register for events, or use HPU online applications and services.  If you elect to voluntarily provide personally identifiable information to HPU via this Website or any of the data entry forms hereon, you are agreeing to the collection and use of such information, in accordance with this Privacy Policy.
This Website does not collect personal information about a user EXCEPT for information that is voluntarily provided to us for the purpose of conducting legitimate business and/or for educational purposes. Information you submit through our websites, such as your name, email, other contact information, may be collected by HPU for marketing, promotion and development purposes, to help us improve the Web site, as well as to respond to your inquiries or to further the transaction that you have requested.  It will be treated confidentially within our institution. Our policy is not to share this information with third parties, except with your consent or as set forth below.
We may reveal personally identifiable information about you to unaffiliated third parties:
if you request or authorize it;
if the information is provided to help complete a transaction for you;
if the information is provided to comply with the law, applicable regulations, governmental and quasi-governmental requests, court orders or subpoenas, to protect HPU’s rights, property or safety or the rights, property or safety of our users or others (e.g., criminal investigations);
if the information is provided to our agents, outside vendors or service providers to perform functions on our behalf (e.g., analyzing data, providing marketing assistance, providing customer service, processing orders, etc.) and then with confidentiality provisions and other protections in place for any personally identifiable information; or
as otherwise described in this Privacy Policy.
We may share information that does not personally identify you without restriction.
HPU will not sell any personal information to third parties for their use in direct marketing, advertising, or promotion of their products or services.
“COOKIE” TECHNOLOGY
Although we may employ "cookie" technology on this website, it will only be used to track non-personal information such as type of browser, operating system, HPU internal transactions (such as forms, online registration, or requests for assistance) and domain names in order to improve our visitors' experience online.  In addition, HPU may track:
The Internet Protocol address of the computer that accessed our Web site
The Web page from which the user accessed the current Web page
The date and time of the user's request
The pages that were visited and the amount of time spent at each page
None of the above-mentioned information is deemed to constitute personal information by the Internet Privacy and Security Act or other applicable laws, including Regulation (EU) 2016/679 General Data Protection Regulation. The information that is collected automatically is used to improve HPU.edu’s content and to help HPU understand how users are interacting with this Website. This information is collected largely for statistical analysis and to determine what information is of most and least interest to our users.
We may use cookies and similar technology to collect aggregate and/or non-personal information about website usage by our visitors and to help us remember you and your preferences when you revisit the websites.  Some of these cookies are erased when you close your browser window and some persist for a period of time. You may be able to decline cookies by adjusting your browser settings but some features of the websites may not function.
We may allow selected third parties to place cookies through the website to provide us with better insights into the use of the website or to allow us to remarket to you or to provide relevant advertising and/or content to you. These third parties may collect information about a user’s online activities over time and across different websites when he or she uses our website. HPU only contracts with third parties who agree to comply with all applicable laws in the use of cookies and similar technology.
We do not use this tool to collect or store your personal information, and it cannot be used to identify who you are.
APPLICATION MATERIALS AND TRANSACTIONS
During your visit to HPU.edu you may voluntary elect to complete a transaction such as an online application or other inquiry, donation or other transaction.  The information collected by HPU, including personal information volunteered by you in completing the transaction, is used by HPU in furtherance of the transaction and may be disclosed by HPU for related purposes, included those purposes that may be reasonably ascertained from the nature and terms of the transaction in which the information was submitted. Any personal information volunteered shall be maintained by the HPU department in accordance with our University Records Retention program and discarded accordingly.
REVIEW AND REQUEST CHANGES TO INFORMATION COLLECTED
If you submit personally-identifying information to HPU via an online form, you may review and request changes be made to that information by contacting the department to whom you submitted the information.  If a form you submitted generated an automatic response that was sent to your email address, you may contact the person or persons identified in that response via the email address provided or you may contact:  help@hpu.edu, if you wish to change your information. If you choose not to receive e-mail or other means of communication from HPU and would prefer not to in the future, you may request that you not receive communications by contacting us at: help@hpu.edu.
Changes to Our Privacy Policy
HPU reserves the right to modify this Privacy Policy at any time. We encourage visitors to frequently check this page for any changes to this Privacy Policy. If we make changes, we will post an updated effective date below. Your continued use of this site after any change in this Privacy Policy will constitute your acceptance of such change.
Special Notice to Parents and Children
All information submitted on this site must comply with the Children's Online Privacy Protection Act, effective April 21, 2000. Detailed information about this Act may be found at http://www.ftc.gov/privacy/privacyinitiatives/childrens.html
POLICY EFFECTIVE DATE:  MARCH 18, 2004POLICY UPDATED:  MAY 25, 2018
